<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Stalkerware on </title>
    <link>https://maynier.eu/tags/stalkerware/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Stalkerware on </description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <copyright>© {year}</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 16 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0100</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://maynier.eu/tags/stalkerware/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>How to Check if an Android Phone has a Stalkerware Installed?</title>
      <link>https://maynier.eu/blog/2021/01/16/how-to-check-if-an-android-phone-has-a-stalkerware-installed/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 16 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>https://maynier.eu/blog/2021/01/16/how-to-check-if-an-android-phone-has-a-stalkerware-installed/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Stalkerwares are malware used in abusive relationships to spy on someone&amp;rsquo;s partner. I have talked quite a bit about it already, see my &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.randhome.io/blog/2017/04/23/lets-talk-about-flexispy/&#34;&gt;previous&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.randhome.io/blog/2020/08/23/some-thoughts-about-stalkerware-and-technology-in-intimate-partner-violence/&#34;&gt;blog posts&lt;/a&gt; for more background information on stalkerware.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;There are different ways to check if a stalkerware is installed on a phone. At &lt;a href=&#34;https://echap.eu.org/&#34;&gt;Echap&lt;/a&gt;, we have written a guide &lt;a href=&#34;https://echap.eu.org/ressources/guides/guide-identifier-des-signes-de-la-presence-dun-logiciel-espion-sur-android/&#34;&gt;to check for configuration settings&lt;/a&gt; on an Android phone (in French). We think it is the easiest way for non-tech people and quite reliable. The &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.ceta.tech.cornell.edu/&#34;&gt;Clinic to End Tech Abuse&lt;/a&gt; has developed a tool called &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/stopipv/isdi&#34;&gt;ISDi&lt;/a&gt; to look for stalkerware based on package names on Android and iOS. More recently, Felix Aimé has released a tool called &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/KasperskyLab/TinyCheck&#34;&gt;TinyCheck&lt;/a&gt; to analyze network traffic from a smartphone, which can be used to identify stalkerware traffic.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Some Thoughts About Stalkerware and Technology in Intimate Partner Violence</title>
      <link>https://maynier.eu/blog/2020/08/23/some-thoughts-about-stalkerware-and-technology-in-intimate-partner-violence/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 23 Aug 2020 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <guid>https://maynier.eu/blog/2020/08/23/some-thoughts-about-stalkerware-and-technology-in-intimate-partner-violence/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;A few years ago, I wrote about &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.randhome.io/blog/2017/04/23/lets-talk-about-flexispy/&#34;&gt;Flexispy&lt;/a&gt; after the company got hacked and some data was released. It was the first time I encountered stalkerware in my work. Since then, I have had many discussions about this creepy market and more generally technology used in intimate partner violence (IPV) with researchers and activists. I think it is the right time to reflect on what we know about stalkerware and what needs to be done on this topic.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Let&#39;s Talk About FlexiSpy</title>
      <link>https://maynier.eu/blog/2017/04/23/lets-talk-about-flexispy/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 23 Apr 2017 22:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://maynier.eu/blog/2017/04/23/lets-talk-about-flexispy/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Introduction&lt;/strong&gt;: I started this blog post to explain the context of FlexiSpy leaks and show some information I have found during my analysis. This information is incomplete and there is still plenty analysis of source code or binaries to be done. I have uploaded the source code and binaries &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/&#34;&gt;on github&lt;/a&gt; so that everyone can help with it. I will try to report in this articles the publications I have seen on it, but feel free to ping me &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/tenacioustek&#34;&gt;on Twitter&lt;/a&gt; if you see new information or have any question.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
