<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title></title>
    <link>https://maynier.eu/</link>
    <description>Recent content on </description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <copyright>© {year}</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 16 Jan 2025 20:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://maynier.eu/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Starting 2025 with a blog post and new resolutions</title>
      <link>https://maynier.eu/blog/2025/01/16/starting-2025-with-a-blog-post-and-new-resolutions/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 16 Jan 2025 20:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://maynier.eu/blog/2025/01/16/starting-2025-with-a-blog-post-and-new-resolutions/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;2025 is here and I have to acknowledge that this blog has been a bit abandoned lately. So now is a good time to bring some life back here and also a good time to reflect on 2024 and what&amp;rsquo;s next.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;reflecting-on-2024&#34;&gt;Reflecting on 2024&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;In many aspects, 2024 has been a rough year with so many crises in the world. Like many people, I have looked with horror at the genocide in Gaza and felt powerless to participate in anything that could prevent it. I have also seen so many people affected by the horrible attacks in Palestine and Lebanon. After many years working in Human Rights, it has been hard to look at &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.foreignaffairs.com/israel/gaza-and-end-rules-based-order&#34;&gt;how inefficient Human Rights and International Law&lt;/a&gt; has been to prevent these massacres. The war in Ukraine is continuing and is not showing any sign of positive resolution, and there have been major political crises with violence against the population in so many countries like Sudan, Kenya or Mozambique. The Trump election in the US and the growing far-right and neo-fascist movement in Europe, US and elsewhere is scary. Capitalism is pushing us slowly but surely into fascism, largely helped by far-right billionaires like Elon Musk, &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Vincent_Bollor%C3%A9&#34;&gt;Vincent Boloré&lt;/a&gt; or &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.disconnect.blog/p/the-conservative-tech-alliance-is-coming-to-canada&#34;&gt;Tobias Lütke&lt;/a&gt;, and it is hard to see any efficient strategy to counter it.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Restriction of European Visitors in US media - an update</title>
      <link>https://maynier.eu/blog/2023/02/27/restriction-of-european-visitors-in-us-media-an-update/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 27 Feb 2023 01:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>https://maynier.eu/blog/2023/02/27/restriction-of-european-visitors-in-us-media-an-update/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In November 2021, I did &lt;a href=&#34;https://maynier.eu/blog/2021/11/24/analyzing-us-media-blocking-of-eu-visitors/&#34;&gt;some testing&lt;/a&gt; to see how many US media were blocking European visitors to avoid complying with GDPR. To my surprise, most of them actually used the &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/HTTP_451&#34;&gt;HTTP 451 code&lt;/a&gt; that was created in reference of Ray Bradbury&amp;rsquo;s Fahrenheit 451 novel.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;figure class=&#34;center&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://maynier.eu/media/gdpr/451.png&#34;&#xA;    alt=&#34;Example of page blocked with HTTP 451 (Source: Wikipedia)&#34;&gt;&lt;figcaption&gt;&#xA;      &lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Example of page blocked with HTTP 451 (Source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/File:Status_code_451_example.png&#34;&gt;Wikipedia&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;    &lt;/figcaption&gt;&#xA;&lt;/figure&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I recently found &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/ercexpo/us-news-domains&#34;&gt;a new list&lt;/a&gt; of over 5000 US media domains established in 2021 by Clemm von Hohenberg, B., Menchen-Trevino, E., Casas, A., Wojcieszak, M., so I decided to run a new series of test based on this list.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>France and Controlling Access to Porn Websites</title>
      <link>https://maynier.eu/blog/2023/02/16/france-and-controlling-access-to-porn-websites/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 16 Feb 2023 01:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>https://maynier.eu/blog/2023/02/16/france-and-controlling-access-to-porn-websites/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;January 2023, and once again the question of limiting access to porn websites for people under the legal majority age is back in the media. It is a question as old as the World Wide Web that is coming back every year with a different angle. In 2020, the French Parliament even passed a law (article &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.legifrance.gouv.fr/codes/article_lc/LEGIARTI000044394218/2021-12-02/&#34;&gt;227-24&lt;/a&gt; of the criminal code) forcing pornography websites to use age filtering more efficient than a simple web form. The problem is that there is currently no reliable and privacy-preserving solution to do that (without even saying that these websites want to limit any friction for their users).&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Analyzing US Media Blocking of EU Visitors</title>
      <link>https://maynier.eu/blog/2021/11/24/analyzing-us-media-blocking-of-eu-visitors/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 24 Nov 2021 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>https://maynier.eu/blog/2021/11/24/analyzing-us-media-blocking-of-eu-visitors/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I have been working and studying technology for over 10 years now, and the one thing I really love  is discovering weird technical quirks you can find on Internet, and what they tell us about society. Things like how &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.washingtonpost.com/news/morning-mix/wp/2016/08/10/lawsuit-how-a-quiet-kansas-home-wound-up-with-600-million-ip-addresses-and-a-world-of-trouble/&#34;&gt;bad geolocation of IP addresses turned the life of a Kansas family into hell&lt;/a&gt; or how to &lt;a href=&#34;https://dictatoralert.org/&#34;&gt;track dictator&amp;rsquo;s aircraft from open flight information&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Among them, I discovered last year that the HTTP code &lt;code&gt;HTTP 451 Unavailable For Legal Reasons&lt;/code&gt; was actually used by some US media to block European visitors as they do not want to comply with GDPR regulation. The code &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/HTTP_451&#34;&gt;451&lt;/a&gt; is actually a reference to Ray Bradbury&amp;rsquo;s book Fahrenheit 451.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How to Check if an Android Phone has a Stalkerware Installed?</title>
      <link>https://maynier.eu/blog/2021/01/16/how-to-check-if-an-android-phone-has-a-stalkerware-installed/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 16 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>https://maynier.eu/blog/2021/01/16/how-to-check-if-an-android-phone-has-a-stalkerware-installed/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Stalkerwares are malware used in abusive relationships to spy on someone&amp;rsquo;s partner. I have talked quite a bit about it already, see my &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.randhome.io/blog/2017/04/23/lets-talk-about-flexispy/&#34;&gt;previous&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.randhome.io/blog/2020/08/23/some-thoughts-about-stalkerware-and-technology-in-intimate-partner-violence/&#34;&gt;blog posts&lt;/a&gt; for more background information on stalkerware.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;There are different ways to check if a stalkerware is installed on a phone. At &lt;a href=&#34;https://echap.eu.org/&#34;&gt;Echap&lt;/a&gt;, we have written a guide &lt;a href=&#34;https://echap.eu.org/ressources/guides/guide-identifier-des-signes-de-la-presence-dun-logiciel-espion-sur-android/&#34;&gt;to check for configuration settings&lt;/a&gt; on an Android phone (in French). We think it is the easiest way for non-tech people and quite reliable. The &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.ceta.tech.cornell.edu/&#34;&gt;Clinic to End Tech Abuse&lt;/a&gt; has developed a tool called &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/stopipv/isdi&#34;&gt;ISDi&lt;/a&gt; to look for stalkerware based on package names on Android and iOS. More recently, Felix Aimé has released a tool called &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/KasperskyLab/TinyCheck&#34;&gt;TinyCheck&lt;/a&gt; to analyze network traffic from a smartphone, which can be used to identify stalkerware traffic.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Analyzing Cobalt Strike for Fun and Profit</title>
      <link>https://maynier.eu/blog/2020/12/20/analyzing-cobalt-strike-for-fun-and-profit/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 20 Dec 2020 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <guid>https://maynier.eu/blog/2020/12/20/analyzing-cobalt-strike-for-fun-and-profit/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I am not sure what happened this year but it seems that Cobalt Strike is now the most used malware around the world, from &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.fireeye.com/blog/threat-research/2020/03/apt41-initiates-global-intrusion-campaign-using-multiple-exploits.html&#34;&gt;APT41&lt;/a&gt; to &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.cybereason.com/blog/operation-cobalt-kitty-apt&#34;&gt;APT32&lt;/a&gt;, even the last &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.fireeye.com/blog/threat-research/2020/12/evasive-attacker-leverages-solarwinds-supply-chain-compromises-with-sunburst-backdoor.html&#34;&gt;SolarWinds supply chain attack&lt;/a&gt; involved Cobalt Strike. Without relaunching the heated debate on publishing offensive tools, this blog post intends to summarize what an analyst needs to know about Cobalt Strike to quickly identify and analyze it during incidents.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;figure&gt;&#xA;    &lt;img src=&#34;https://maynier.eu/media/cobaltstrike/everywhere.jpg&#34; style=&#34;max-width:400px&#34;/&gt;&#xA;   &#xA;&lt;/figure&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;finding-cobalt-strike-servers&#34;&gt;Finding Cobalt Strike Servers&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;A few months ago, the Salesforce security team &lt;a href=&#34;https://engineering.salesforce.com/easily-identify-malicious-servers-on-the-internet-with-jarm-e095edac525a&#34;&gt;published&lt;/a&gt; a new active fingerprint tool called &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/salesforce/jarm&#34;&gt;JARM&lt;/a&gt;. It is the active equivalent to &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/salesforce/ja3&#34;&gt;JA3&lt;/a&gt; they published last year. It generates a fingerprint based on the TLS configuration of a remote server, such as the TLS version or the TLS extensions, without considering the certificate. It is especially useful to identify custom web servers used by some tools, and Cobalt Strike is one of them.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Investigating Infrastructure Links with Passive DNS and Whois Data</title>
      <link>https://maynier.eu/blog/2020/08/30/investigating-infrastructure-links-with-passive-dns-and-whois-data/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 30 Aug 2020 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <guid>https://maynier.eu/blog/2020/08/30/investigating-infrastructure-links-with-passive-dns-and-whois-data/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;I am republishing here the guide on using passive DNS and Whois data in investigation that I published earlier this year on the &lt;a href=&#34;https://citizenevidence.org/2020/06/26/investigating-infrastructure-links-with-passive-dns-and-whois-data/&#34;&gt;Amnesty Citizen Evidence Lab website&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;hr&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Many disinformation or malware campaigns rely on a computer architecture based on several servers and domains, and even if they often try to hide the infrastructure, it has to be accessible online. Investigating these infrastructure links is often a good way to get a broader view of the campaign. This is one of the tools we use in our investigations at &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.amnesty.org/en/tech/&#34;&gt;Amnesty Tech&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Some Thoughts About Stalkerware and Technology in Intimate Partner Violence</title>
      <link>https://maynier.eu/blog/2020/08/23/some-thoughts-about-stalkerware-and-technology-in-intimate-partner-violence/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 23 Aug 2020 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <guid>https://maynier.eu/blog/2020/08/23/some-thoughts-about-stalkerware-and-technology-in-intimate-partner-violence/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;A few years ago, I wrote about &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.randhome.io/blog/2017/04/23/lets-talk-about-flexispy/&#34;&gt;Flexispy&lt;/a&gt; after the company got hacked and some data was released. It was the first time I encountered stalkerware in my work. Since then, I have had many discussions about this creepy market and more generally technology used in intimate partner violence (IPV) with researchers and activists. I think it is the right time to reflect on what we know about stalkerware and what needs to be done on this topic.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Analyzing Shellcodes with Miasm for Fun and Profit</title>
      <link>https://maynier.eu/blog/2020/04/04/analyzing-shellcodes-with-miasm-for-fun-and-profit/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 04 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>https://maynier.eu/blog/2020/04/04/analyzing-shellcodes-with-miasm-for-fun-and-profit/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Shellcodes are an interesting piece of software because they have to run with unusual constraints. They are also small enough to be used to learn new tools. I have been wanting to learn to use &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/cea-sec/miasm&#34;&gt;miasm&lt;/a&gt; for a long time (since I saw the first presentation at SSTIC some years ago), I finally used a few nights of confinement to learn that, here is a short summary.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;linux-shellcode&#34;&gt;Linux shellcode&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Let&amp;rsquo;s start with a Linux shellcode as they are less complex than Windows shellcodes.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Targeted Attacks Against Civil Society : What is New in 2019?</title>
      <link>https://maynier.eu/blog/2019/12/02/targeted-attacks-against-civil-society-what-is-new-in-2019/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Dec 2019 00:00:02 -0500</pubDate>
      <guid>https://maynier.eu/blog/2019/12/02/targeted-attacks-against-civil-society-what-is-new-in-2019/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h3 id=&#34;tldr&#34;&gt;TL;DR&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;New trends in targeted attacks against civil society in 2019 :&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;More attacks against smartphones, some attacks are using 0-days and we don&amp;rsquo;t know how to be effectively protected against them, but many attacks are using exploits against fixed bugs in Android&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Phishing attacks bypassing 2 Factor Authentication solutions other than hardware keys are common now. We have to consider that most attacks will support that in the future, and move to hardware tokens for 2FA&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;OAuth attacks are still there and will likely be there for some time. As they bypass many protections against phishing, people need to be aware of them and check their OAuth access regularly.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;h3 id=&#34;targeted-attacks-against-civil-society--what-is-new-in-2019&#34;&gt;Targeted Attacks Against Civil Society : What is New in 2019?&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;10 years ago, the &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.nartv.org/mirror/ghostnet.pdf&#34;&gt;GhostNet report&lt;/a&gt; published by the Citizen Lab made quite a buzz; it described an important coordinated effort of compromising computers over the world, from the embassy of India in the US to PetroVietnam. It was one of the first times that an attack campaign of that scale was revealed, but what made it especially important is that this campaign was discovered when researchers identified attacks against the Tibetan community in exile, and more specifically against the Office of the Dalai Lama.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>2019 OSINT Guide</title>
      <link>https://maynier.eu/blog/2019/01/05/2019-osint-guide/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 05 Jan 2019 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>https://maynier.eu/blog/2019/01/05/2019-osint-guide/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I have been doing a lot of Open-Source Intelligence (OSINT) lately, so to celebrate 2019, I decided to summarize a lot of tips and tricks I have learned in this guide. Of course, it is not the perfect guide (no guide is), but I hope it will help beginners to learn, and experienced OSINT hackers to discover new tricks&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h1 id=&#34;methodology&#34;&gt;Methodology&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The classic OSINT methodology you will find everywhere is strait-forward:&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Harpoon: an OSINT / Threat Intelligence tool</title>
      <link>https://maynier.eu/blog/2018/02/23/harpoon-an-osint-/-threat-intelligence-tool/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 23 Feb 2018 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <guid>https://maynier.eu/blog/2018/02/23/harpoon-an-osint-/-threat-intelligence-tool/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;tldr&#34;&gt;TL;DR&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Harpoon&lt;/strong&gt; is a tool to automate threat intelligence and open source intelligence tasks. It is written in Python 3 and organised in plugins so the idea is to have one plugin per platform or task. The code is on &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/Te-k/harpoon&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Github&lt;/a&gt;, feel free to open &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/Te-k/harpoon/issues&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;issues&lt;/a&gt; and propose &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/Te-k/harpoon/pulls&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Pull Requests&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Install and config:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;div class=&#34;highlight&#34;&gt;&lt;pre tabindex=&#34;0&#34; style=&#34;color:#f8f8f2;background-color:#272822;-moz-tab-size:4;-o-tab-size:4;tab-size:4;&#34;&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-bash&#34; data-lang=&#34;bash&#34;&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;display:flex;&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;pip install git+ssh://git@github.com/Te-k/harpoon  --process-dependency-links&#xA;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;display:flex;&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;npm install -g phantomjs&#xA;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;display:flex;&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;harpoon config -u&#xA;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;display:flex;&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;harpoon config&#xA;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;Then check how to use every module with &lt;code&gt;harpoon help MODULE&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Another PE tool</title>
      <link>https://maynier.eu/blog/2018/02/04/another-pe-tool/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 04 Feb 2018 17:08:02 -0500</pubDate>
      <guid>https://maynier.eu/blog/2018/02/04/another-pe-tool/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Analyzing PE files is a basic task in reverse engineering in order to understand their structure, look for anything interesting before going more in depth into the reverse engineering in itself. There are countless tools to do that, on Windows I use &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.winitor.com/&#34;&gt;PeStudio&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;http://wjradburn.com/software/&#34;&gt;PEView&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.angusj.com/resourcehacker/&#34;&gt;Resource Hacker&lt;/a&gt;. But most of the time I want to have a first view of the file before starting my Virtual Machine, so I was looking for a CLI tool on Linux. There is of course &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/Te-k/analyst-scripts/blob/master/pe/pescanner.py&#34;&gt;PEScanner&lt;/a&gt; published by Michael Ligh with the good &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.wiley.com/en-us/Malware&amp;#43;Analyst%27s&amp;#43;Cookbook&amp;#43;and&amp;#43;DVD%3A&amp;#43;Tools&amp;#43;and&amp;#43;Techniques&amp;#43;for&amp;#43;Fighting&amp;#43;Malicious&amp;#43;Code-p-9780470613030&#34;&gt;Malware Analyst&amp;rsquo;s Cookbook&lt;/a&gt; but it is a bit outdated (python2 only) and I like to write my own tools to be sure I understand how they work and what are their limits.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Google Advanced Protection</title>
      <link>https://maynier.eu/blog/2017/11/05/google-advanced-protection/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 05 Nov 2017 00:00:42 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>https://maynier.eu/blog/2017/11/05/google-advanced-protection/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Last week, Google has added a new set of security features in Gmail called &lt;a href=&#34;https://landing.google.com/advancedprotection/&#34;&gt;&amp;ldquo;Advanced Protection&amp;rdquo;&lt;/a&gt;, specifically for high-risk users. It was widely covered the media (&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.wired.com/story/google-advanced-protection-locks-down-accounts/&#34;&gt;Wired&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.theverge.com/2017/10/17/16488572/google-advanced-protection-phishing-fraud-security-keys&#34;&gt;The Verge&lt;/a&gt; or &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.reuters.com/article/us-google-cyber/google-launches-advanced-gmail-security-features-for-high-risk-users-idUSKBN1CM1GP&#34;&gt;Reuters&lt;/a&gt;) and quickly started a debate about whether Google is &lt;a href=&#34;https://motherboard.vice.com/en_us/article/kz74ym/google-gmail-advanced-protection-security-keys-yubikey&#34;&gt;the most secure email provider on the planet&lt;/a&gt; or if &lt;a href=&#34;https://motherboard.vice.com/en_us/article/pa3ye7/protonmail-gmail-security-comparison&#34;&gt;ProtonMail can compete&lt;/a&gt;. The main point here to me (and it has been said by many other people everywhere) is whether you trust Google to keep your data or not, depending on your threat model and your opinion about privacy.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Let&#39;s Talk About FlexiSpy</title>
      <link>https://maynier.eu/blog/2017/04/23/lets-talk-about-flexispy/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 23 Apr 2017 22:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://maynier.eu/blog/2017/04/23/lets-talk-about-flexispy/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Introduction&lt;/strong&gt;: I started this blog post to explain the context of FlexiSpy leaks and show some information I have found during my analysis. This information is incomplete and there is still plenty analysis of source code or binaries to be done. I have uploaded the source code and binaries &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/&#34;&gt;on github&lt;/a&gt; so that everyone can help with it. I will try to report in this articles the publications I have seen on it, but feel free to ping me &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/tenacioustek&#34;&gt;on Twitter&lt;/a&gt; if you see new information or have any question.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>#privacy</title>
      <link>https://maynier.eu/privacy/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 Aug 2016 21:21:05 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>https://maynier.eu/privacy/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;There are now more and more privacy abuse everywhere, so even though we feel it, it&amp;rsquo;s often hard to understand the daily privacy demolition. To help me, I started a list of privacy abuse cases here (likely out of date, I have considered only cases by commercial companies for now, if you see additional cases, poke me on &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/tenacioustek&#34;&gt;Twitter&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;2016&#34;&gt;2016&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;2016/08/06 &lt;a href=&#34;http://motherboard.vice.com/read/dildo-data-hacking&#34;&gt;The Internet of Dildos Is Watching You&lt;/a&gt; : Connected sextoys sending intensity settings and temperature to the manufacturer in real-time&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;2016/08/03 &lt;a href=&#34;http://thenextweb.com/insider/2016/08/03/comcast-isps-should-be-able-to-sell-your-web-history-to-advertisers/&#34;&gt;Comcast: ISPs should be able to sell your Web history to advertisers&lt;/a&gt; (Comcast only asked to the Federal Communications Commission, it&amp;rsquo;s apparently not done yet)&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;2016/08/02 &lt;a href=&#34;https://blog.lukaszolejnik.com/battery-status-readout-as-a-privacy-risk/&#34;&gt;Battery Status readout as a privacy risk&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;2016/07/21 &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.theguardian.com/technology/2016/jul/20/france-microsoft-user-data-collection-privacy&#34;&gt;France orders Microsoft to stop collecting excessive user data&lt;/a&gt; : MS started to process information an all the apps downloaded and installed by a user and the time spent on each one (linked to an email account now)&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;2016/05/04 &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.theguardian.com/technology/2016/may/04/google-deepmind-access-healthcare-data-patients&#34;&gt;Google given access to healthcare data of up to 1.6 million patients&lt;/a&gt; : DeepMind (a Google owned company) accessed patient information in an agreement with the Royal Free NHS trust to develop data analysis software&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;2015&#34;&gt;2015&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;2015/01/10 (at least) &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/atom/atom/issues/4966&#34;&gt;Metrics enabled by default in Github Atom editor&lt;/a&gt; : Atom sends metrics about the tool usage to Google Servers without user knowledge (it was apparently updated then to inform the user). The id per user chosen is a SHA-1 of the MAC address. Fixed the 9th of August 2016.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;2015/02/13 &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.theguardian.com/technology/2015/mar/13/smart-barbie-that-can-listen-to-your-kids-privacy-fears-mattel&#34;&gt;Privacy fears over &amp;lsquo;smart&amp;rsquo; Barbie that can listen to your kids&lt;/a&gt; : New connected barbies send recordings to manufacturer sender for voice-recognition, and can potentially sell recordings to third parties.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;2013&#34;&gt;2013&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;2013/08/07 &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.huffingtonpost.com/2013/07/08/att-selling-data_n_3561263.html&#34;&gt;AT&amp;amp;T Is Going To Start Selling Your Data&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;2013/06/24 &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.theguardian.com/business/2013/jun/24/barclays-bank-sell-customer-data&#34;&gt;Barclays to sell customer data&lt;/a&gt; : Barclays Bank start to sell spending habits about 13million customers&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;2013/05/22 &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.huffingtonpost.com/2013/05/22/verizon-selling-customer-data_n_3320680.html&#34;&gt;Verizon Selling Customers’ Cell Phone Data&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;2013/04/05 &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.journaldunet.com/solutions/dsi/trophees-de-l-innovation-big-data/3e-prix.shtml&#34;&gt;SFR has a project of commercialising geographic data of its customers&lt;/a&gt; (French), use cases cited : understand the origin of people arriving in a supermarket, or understanding people travels in public transports.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;2010&#34;&gt;2010&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;2010/04/01 Google Wi-Spy abuse case : Google cars collected Wifi data while driving (mostly illegally). The intercept has done an clear overview in &lt;a href=&#34;https://theintercept.com/2016/08/09/privacy-scandal-haunts-pokemon-gos-ceo/&#34;&gt;this article&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Openssh backdoor used on compromised Linux servers</title>
      <link>https://maynier.eu/blog/2016/08/01/openssh-backdoor-used-on-compromised-linux-servers/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Aug 2016 14:53:42 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>https://maynier.eu/blog/2016/08/01/openssh-backdoor-used-on-compromised-linux-servers/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Olà,&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Some times ago, I have installed honeypot services on one of my servers, in order to see what happens in the real outside world. I especially installed the &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/cowrie/cowrie&#34;&gt;cowrie&lt;/a&gt; ssh honeypot which simulate a Linux shell and gather binaries that people want to install on the server (this tool is awesome, check &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/micheloosterhof/cowrie/wiki/How-to-setup-Cowrie-on-Debian&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt; to install it).&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;cowrie-ssh&#34;&gt;Cowrie ssh&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;This honeypot is really fun, because it records everything done during an attack, and record the whole tty session which can be replayed. If the attacker tries to download a file, cowrie automatically downloads it and stores it in a dedicated directory. In my case, I have only allowed one correct password (but an easily one : root123), so most of my logs are failed authentications:&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Machine learning for malware detection</title>
      <link>https://maynier.eu/blog/2016/07/16/machine-learning-for-malware-detection/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 16 Jul 2016 12:52:42 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>https://maynier.eu/blog/2016/07/16/machine-learning-for-malware-detection/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Plop,&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I have been reading many articles about Machine Learning recently, and it seems to be the new hype technology so I wanted to play a bit with these algorithms to better understand the principles behind it. If you don&amp;rsquo;t know machine learning, you should to read this &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.r2d3.us/visual-intro-to-machine-learning-part-1/&#34;&gt;awesome article&lt;/a&gt; or &lt;a href=&#34;https://redshiftzero.github.io/2015/08/29/Manipulation-and-Machine-Learning/&#34;&gt;this one&lt;/a&gt;. This article was largely inspired by &lt;a href=&#34;https://blog.socialcops.com/engineering/machine-learning-python&#34;&gt;this one which analyze the Titanic data&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;machine-learning-and-classification&#34;&gt;Machine Learning and Classification&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;So the idea of machine learning is to let the algorithm learn by itself the best parameters from data in order to make good predictions. There are many different applications, in our case we will consider using machine learning algorithm to classify binaries between legitimate and malicious binaries. This idea is &lt;a href=&#34;http://ieeexplore.ieee.org/xpl/login.jsp?tp=&amp;amp;arnumber=924286&amp;amp;url=http%3A%2F%2Fieeexplore.ieee.org%2Fxpls%2Fabs_all.jsp%3Farnumber%3D924286&#34;&gt;not&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;http://ieeexplore.ieee.org/xpl/login.jsp?tp=&amp;amp;arnumber=1297538&amp;amp;url=http%3A%2F%2Fieeexplore.ieee.org%2Fxpls%2Fabs_all.jsp%3Farnumber%3D1297538&#34;&gt;new&lt;/a&gt; and Adobe has even released a tool called &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/adobe-security/Malware-classifier&#34;&gt;Adobe Malware Classifier&lt;/a&gt; at &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.blackhat.com/html/webcast/webcast-2012-polymorphicmalware.html&#34;&gt;Black Hat 2012&lt;/a&gt; but it will be a nice exercice to see how to use machine learning.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Comparison of php scanners</title>
      <link>https://maynier.eu/blog/2016/05/14/comparison-of-php-scanners/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 14 May 2016 17:44:19 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>https://maynier.eu/blog/2016/05/14/comparison-of-php-scanners/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Hi there!&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I have recently looked different compromised websites on github, mostly using outdated Wordpress/Joomla/Drupal versions. In these cases, I often have to go through many different files to find the malicious one, whether added on the website or added to legitimate files. Here is a short summary of the different tools to detect them.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;clamav&#34;&gt;ClamAV&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.clamav.net/&#34;&gt;ClamAV&lt;/a&gt; is an open-source antivirus developed for different platform, but also one of the seldom antivirus used on Linux. It has a complex signature format with many open signature provided by the community (more than 3 700 000 according to wikipedia). And the good news, is that &lt;a href=&#34;http://blog.clamav.net/2015/06/clamav-099b-meets-yara.html&#34;&gt;it supports Yara&lt;/a&gt; since last year!&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>#references</title>
      <link>https://maynier.eu/references/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 May 2016 01:07:16 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>https://maynier.eu/references/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Here is a list of references regarding security topics and hacktivism:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;political-organizations&#34;&gt;Political Organizations&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Here are several awesome organization regarding online freedom:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;EFF&lt;/strong&gt; : The Electronic Frontier Foundation fights for digital freedom in many different ways (legal fights, press review, development of technical tools&amp;hellip;). See their &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.eff.org/&#34;&gt;website&lt;/a&gt; and their &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/EFF&#34;&gt;Twitter account&lt;/a&gt;. Here is a list of EFF projects I like:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://letsencrypt.org/&#34;&gt;Let&amp;rsquo;s Encrypt&lt;/a&gt; is a free certificate authority&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.eff.org/en/privacybadger&#34;&gt;Privacy badger&lt;/a&gt; is a Chrome/Firefox extension to block spying ads and invisible trackers&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.eff.org/https-everywhere&#34;&gt;HTTPs Everywhere&lt;/a&gt; is a browser extension to use HTTPs by default on main websites&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Citizen Lab&lt;/strong&gt; is a research group based in the University of Toronto which focus its researchs on human rights and digital surveillance. They have done amazing analysis of targeted attacks by governments on citizen (like &lt;a href=&#34;https://citizenlab.org/2016/04/between-hong-kong-and-burma/&#34;&gt;this one&lt;/a&gt; or &lt;a href=&#34;https://citizenlab.org/2016/03/shifting-tactics/&#34;&gt;this one&lt;/a&gt;). See &lt;a href=&#34;https://citizenlab.org/&#34;&gt;their website&lt;/a&gt; or &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/CitizenLab&#34;&gt;twitter account&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Resources</title>
      <link>https://maynier.eu/resources/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 May 2016 01:07:16 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>https://maynier.eu/resources/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This page gathers some useful guides and resources on digital security.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;figure&gt;&#xA;    &lt;img src=&#34;https://maynier.eu/media/robot_charging.jpg&#34; style=&#34;max-width:300px&#34;/&gt;&#xA;   &#xA;    &lt;center&gt;&#xA;        &lt;small&gt;&lt;i&gt;&#xA;        &#xA;        &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.mattdixon.co.uk/&#34;&gt; &#xA;            Drawing by Matt Dixon&#xA;        &lt;/a&gt; &#xA;            &lt;/i&gt;&lt;/small&gt; &#xA;    &lt;/center&gt;&#xA;    &#xA;&lt;/figure&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;general-digital-security-guides&#34;&gt;General Digital Security Guides&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The main resources on digital security are:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://ssd.eff.org/&#34;&gt;Surveillance Self-Defense&lt;/a&gt; by &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.eff.org/&#34;&gt;EFF&lt;/a&gt; is the main reference, it is available in 11 languages and well maintained.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://securityplanner.consumerreports.org/#/&#34;&gt;Security Planner&lt;/a&gt; by &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.consumerreports.org/&#34;&gt;Consumer Reports&lt;/a&gt; is an easy to use platform to get practical recommendations&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://securityinabox.org/en/&#34;&gt;Security In a Box&lt;/a&gt; is a very good resource, but not maintained anymore and many guides and articles are now outdated.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;In French, le &lt;a href=&#34;https://guide.boum.org/&#34;&gt;Guide d&amp;rsquo;autodéfense numérique&lt;/a&gt; is a good in-depth manual (that may not fit for people looking for quick answers)&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;on-phishing-and-malware-attacks&#34;&gt;On Phishing and Malware attacks&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;If you want to understand phishing and malware attacks more specifically:&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>About Me</title>
      <link>https://maynier.eu/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 29 Apr 2016 14:51:26 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>https://maynier.eu/about/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I am Etienne &amp;ldquo;tek&amp;rdquo; Maynier, an activist, security analyst and researcher.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;figure&gt;&#xA;    &lt;img src=&#34;https://maynier.eu/avatar.jpg&#34; style=&#34;max-width:250px&#34;/&gt;&#xA;   &#xA;    &lt;center&gt;&#xA;        &lt;small&gt;&lt;i&gt;&#xA;        &#xA;        &lt;a href=&#34;https://lila.ink/&#34;&gt; &#xA;            Drawing by _lila*&#xA;        &lt;/a&gt; &#xA;            &lt;/i&gt;&lt;/small&gt; &#xA;    &lt;/center&gt;&#xA;    &#xA;&lt;/figure&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I am currently working as a Technologist in the infosec team of &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.hrw.org/&#34;&gt;Human Rights Watch&lt;/a&gt; to protect the organization against digital threats.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Previously, I cofounded and was an active member of &lt;a href=&#34;https://echap.eu.org/&#34;&gt;Echap&lt;/a&gt;, a non profit supporting women shelter on technology, from 2020 to 2025. I was &lt;a href=&#34;https://foundation.mozilla.org/en/fellowships/&#34;&gt;a Mozilla Open Web Fellow&lt;/a&gt; in 2016 - 2017, a research fellow at &lt;a href=&#34;https://citizenlab.ca/&#34;&gt;the Citizen Lab&lt;/a&gt; from June 2017 to April 2021, and worked for &lt;a href=&#34;https://amnesty.org/&#34;&gt;Amnesty International&lt;/a&gt; from 2019 to 2023.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How to contact me?</title>
      <link>https://maynier.eu/contact/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 29 Apr 2016 14:51:26 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>https://maynier.eu/contact/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;You can contact me securely in the following ways:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;figure&gt;&#xA;    &lt;img src=&#34;https://maynier.eu/media/robot_contact.jpg&#34; style=&#34;max-width:300px&#34;/&gt;&#xA;   &#xA;    &lt;center&gt;&#xA;        &lt;small&gt;&lt;i&gt;&#xA;        &#xA;        &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.mattdixon.co.uk/&#34;&gt; &#xA;            Drawing by Matt Dixon&#xA;        &lt;/a&gt; &#xA;            &lt;/i&gt;&lt;/small&gt; &#xA;    &lt;/center&gt;&#xA;    &#xA;&lt;/figure&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;By email: you can contact me at etienne &lt;em&gt;AT&lt;/em&gt; maynier &lt;em&gt;DOT&lt;/em&gt; eu, if possible using &lt;a href=&#34;https://maynier.eu/key.txt&#34;&gt;this public GPG key&lt;/a&gt; (Fingerprint &lt;em&gt;6861 626E B4A8 74F5 D794 ED0C 5FC6 A564 4D8A E276&lt;/em&gt;) or a protonmail account.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;On &lt;a href=&#34;https://wire.com/en/&#34;&gt;Wire&lt;/a&gt;: @tekk&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;On Signal/WhatsApp: the easiest way is likely to send me a DM on Mastodon (@tek@todon.eu) or an email, asking for my phone number and explaining briefly why&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;If you do not need a high level of security, you can still email me or send me a Mastodon DM.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Projects</title>
      <link>https://maynier.eu/projects/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 29 Apr 2016 14:51:26 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>https://maynier.eu/projects/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Here are some personal projects I have been working on:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;figure&gt;&#xA;    &lt;img src=&#34;https://maynier.eu/media/robot_patience.jpg&#34; style=&#34;max-width:300px&#34;/&gt;&#xA;   &#xA;    &lt;center&gt;&#xA;        &lt;small&gt;&lt;i&gt;&#xA;        &#xA;        &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.mattdixon.co.uk/&#34;&gt; &#xA;            Drawing by Matt Dixon&#xA;        &lt;/a&gt; &#xA;            &lt;/i&gt;&lt;/small&gt; &#xA;    &lt;/center&gt;&#xA;    &#xA;&lt;/figure&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;tools&#34;&gt;Tools&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;I am one of the developer and maintainer of the &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/mvt-project/mvt&#34;&gt;MVT Toolkit&lt;/a&gt; that allows to forensically analyze smartphones.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/Te-k/harpoon&#34;&gt;Harpoon&lt;/a&gt; is a python CLI tool to query OSINT and Threat Intelligence platforms (see &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.randhome.io/blog/2018/02/23/harpoon-an-osint-/-threat-intelligence-tool/&#34;&gt;this blog post about it&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/Te-k/stalkerware-indicators&#34;&gt;Indicators of stalkerware&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Some CLI tools to analyze &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/Te-k/pecli&#34;&gt;PE Files&lt;/a&gt; or &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/Te-k/apkcli&#34;&gt;APK files&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Several libraries for threat intelligence such as &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/Te-k/pysafebrowsing&#34;&gt;pysafebrowsing&lt;/a&gt; or &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/Te-k/pycrtsh&#34;&gt;pycrtsh&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Some scripts that may be useful &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/Te-k/analyst-scripts&#34;&gt;for security analysts&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;guides&#34;&gt;Guides&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;I am convinced that civil society would benefit from having more forensic knowledge, I have written a &lt;a href=&#34;https://guides.securitywithoutborders.org/guide-to-quick-forensics/&#34;&gt;Guide to Quick Forensics&lt;/a&gt; with &lt;a href=&#34;https://nex.sx/&#34;&gt;Claudio Guarnieri&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;I have written an &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.randhome.io/blog/2019/01/05/2019-osint-guide/&#34;&gt;OSINT guide&lt;/a&gt; in 2019 that was &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.assoeunomia.fr/2019/03/10/guide-dinvestigation-utiliser-les-sources-ouvertes/&#34;&gt;translated in French&lt;/a&gt; by Eunomia and in &lt;a href=&#34;https://scientia-security.github.io/translation/2019-OSINT-Guide&#34;&gt;Japanese&lt;/a&gt; by &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.linkedin.com/in/tomohisaishikawa/&#34;&gt;Tomohisa Ishikawa&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;I have helped write &lt;a href=&#34;https://echap.eu.org/ressources/&#34;&gt;several security guides&lt;/a&gt; for women shelters with the &lt;a href=&#34;https://echap.eu.org/&#34;&gt;Echap non-profit&lt;/a&gt; (in French)&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;research&#34;&gt;Research&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;I maintain an online bibliography on technology used in intimate partner violence, called &lt;a href=&#34;https://ipvtechbib.randhome.io/&#34;&gt;IPVTechBib&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
