<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts on Tek&#39;s blog</title>
    <link>https://www.randhome.io/post/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Posts on Tek&#39;s blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 04 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0200</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://www.randhome.io/post/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Analyzing Shellcodes with Miasm for Fun and Profit</title>
      <link>https://www.randhome.io/blog/2020/04/04/analyzing-shellcodes-with-miasm-for-fun-and-profit/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 04 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.randhome.io/blog/2020/04/04/analyzing-shellcodes-with-miasm-for-fun-and-profit/</guid>
      <description>Shellcodes are an interesting piece of software because they have to run with unusual constraints. They are also small enough to be used to learn new tools. I have been wanting to learn to use miasm for a long time (since I saw the first presentation at SSTIC some years ago), I finally used a few nights of confinement to learn that, here is a short summary.
Linux shellcode Let&amp;rsquo;s start with a Linux shellcode as they are less complex than Windows shellcodes.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Targeted Attacks Against Civil Society : What is New in 2019?</title>
      <link>https://www.randhome.io/blog/2019/12/02/targeted-attacks-against-civil-society-what-is-new-in-2019/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Dec 2019 00:00:02 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.randhome.io/blog/2019/12/02/targeted-attacks-against-civil-society-what-is-new-in-2019/</guid>
      <description>TL;DR New trends in targeted attacks against civil society in 2019 :
 More attacks against smartphones, some attacks are using 0-days and we don&amp;rsquo;t know how to be effectively protected against them, but many attacks are using exploits against fixed bugs in Android Phishing attacks bypassing 2 Factor Authentication solutions other than hardware keys are common now. We have to consider that most attacks will support that in the future, and move to hardware tokens for 2FA OAuth attacks are still there and will likely be there for some time.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>2019 OSINT Guide</title>
      <link>https://www.randhome.io/blog/2019/01/05/2019-osint-guide/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 05 Jan 2019 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.randhome.io/blog/2019/01/05/2019-osint-guide/</guid>
      <description>I have been doing a lot of Open-Source Intelligence (OSINT) lately, so to celebrate 2019, I decided to summarize a lot of tips and tricks I have learned in this guide. Of course, it is not the perfect guide (no guide is), but I hope it will help beginners to learn, and experienced OSINT hackers to discover new tricks
Methodology The classic OSINT methodology you will find everywhere is strait-forward:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Harpoon: an OSINT / Threat Intelligence tool</title>
      <link>https://www.randhome.io/blog/2018/02/23/harpoon-an-osint-/-threat-intelligence-tool/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 23 Feb 2018 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.randhome.io/blog/2018/02/23/harpoon-an-osint-/-threat-intelligence-tool/</guid>
      <description>TL;DR Harpoon is a tool to automate threat intelligence and open source intelligence tasks. It is written in Python 3 and organised in plugins so the idea is to have one plugin per platform or task. The code is on Github, feel free to open issuesand propose Pull Requests.
Install and config:
pip install git+ssh://git@github.com/Te-k/harpoon --process-dependency-links npm install -g phantomjs harpoon config -u harpoon config Then check how to use every module with harpoon help MODULE</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Another PE tool</title>
      <link>https://www.randhome.io/blog/2018/02/04/another-pe-tool/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 04 Feb 2018 17:08:02 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.randhome.io/blog/2018/02/04/another-pe-tool/</guid>
      <description>Analyzing PE files is a basic task in reverse engineering in order to understand their structure, look for anything interesting before going more in depth into the reverse engineering in itself. There are countless tools to do that, on Windows I use PeStudio, PEView and Resource Hacker. But most of the time I want to have a first view of the file before starting my Virtual Machine, so I was looking for a CLI tool on Linux.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Google Advanced Protection</title>
      <link>https://www.randhome.io/blog/2017/11/05/google-advanced-protection/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 05 Nov 2017 00:00:42 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.randhome.io/blog/2017/11/05/google-advanced-protection/</guid>
      <description>Last week, Google has added a new set of security features in Gmail called &amp;ldquo;Advanced Protection&amp;rdquo;, specifically for high-risk users. It was widely covered the media (Wired, The Verge or Reuters) and quickly started a debate about whether Google is the most secure email provider on the planet or if ProtonMail can compete. The main point here to me (and it has been said by many other people everywhere) is whether you trust Google to keep your data or not, depending on your threat model and your opinion about privacy.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Let&#39;s Talk About FlexiSpy</title>
      <link>https://www.randhome.io/blog/2017/04/23/lets-talk-about-flexispy/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 23 Apr 2017 22:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.randhome.io/blog/2017/04/23/lets-talk-about-flexispy/</guid>
      <description>Introduction: I started this blog post to explain the context of FlexiSpy leaks and show some information I have found during my analysis. This information is incomplete and there is still plenty analysis of source code or binaries to be done. I have uploaded the source code and binaries on github so that everyone can help with it. I will try to report in this articles the publications I have seen on it, but feel free to ping me on Twitter if you see new information or have any question.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Openssh backdoor used on compromised Linux servers</title>
      <link>https://www.randhome.io/blog/2016/08/01/openssh-backdoor-used-on-compromised-linux-servers/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Aug 2016 14:53:42 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.randhome.io/blog/2016/08/01/openssh-backdoor-used-on-compromised-linux-servers/</guid>
      <description>Olà,
Some times ago, I have installed honeypot services on one of my servers, in order to see what happens in the real outside world. I especially installed the cowrie ssh honeypot which simulate a Linux shell and gather binaries that people want to install on the server (this tool is awesome, check here to install it).
Cowrie ssh This honeypot is really fun, because it records everything done during an attack, and record the whole tty session which can be replayed.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Machine learning for malware detection</title>
      <link>https://www.randhome.io/blog/2016/07/16/machine-learning-for-malware-detection/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 16 Jul 2016 12:52:42 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.randhome.io/blog/2016/07/16/machine-learning-for-malware-detection/</guid>
      <description>Plop,
I have been reading many articles about Machine Learning recently, and it seems to be the new hype technology so I wanted to play a bit with these algorithms to better understand the principles behind it. If you don&amp;rsquo;t know machine learning, you should to read this awesome article or this one. This article was largely inspired by this one which analyze the Titanic data.
Machine Learning and Classification So the idea of machine learning is to let the algorithm learn by itself the best parameters from data in order to make good predictions.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Comparison of php scanners</title>
      <link>https://www.randhome.io/blog/2016/05/14/comparison-of-php-scanners/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 14 May 2016 17:44:19 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.randhome.io/blog/2016/05/14/comparison-of-php-scanners/</guid>
      <description>Hi there!
I have recently looked different compromised websites on github, mostly using outdated Wordpress/Joomla/Drupal versions. In these cases, I often have to go through many different files to find the malicious one, whether added on the website or added to legitimate files. Here is a short summary of the different tools to detect them.
ClamAV ClamAV is an open-source antivirus developed for different platform, but also one of the seldom antivirus used on Linux.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>