<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Blog on </title>
    <link>https://maynier.eu/tags/blog/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Blog on </description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <copyright>© {year}</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 16 Jan 2025 20:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://maynier.eu/tags/blog/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Starting 2025 with a blog post and new resolutions</title>
      <link>https://maynier.eu/blog/2025/01/16/starting-2025-with-a-blog-post-and-new-resolutions/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 16 Jan 2025 20:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://maynier.eu/blog/2025/01/16/starting-2025-with-a-blog-post-and-new-resolutions/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;2025 is here and I have to acknowledge that this blog has been a bit abandoned lately. So now is a good time to bring some life back here and also a good time to reflect on 2024 and what&amp;rsquo;s next.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;reflecting-on-2024&#34;&gt;Reflecting on 2024&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;In many aspects, 2024 has been a rough year with so many crises in the world. Like many people, I have looked with horror at the genocide in Gaza and felt powerless to participate in anything that could prevent it. I have also seen so many people affected by the horrible attacks in Palestine and Lebanon. After many years working in Human Rights, it has been hard to look at &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.foreignaffairs.com/israel/gaza-and-end-rules-based-order&#34;&gt;how inefficient Human Rights and International Law&lt;/a&gt; has been to prevent these massacres. The war in Ukraine is continuing and is not showing any sign of positive resolution, and there have been major political crises with violence against the population in so many countries like Sudan, Kenya or Mozambique. The Trump election in the US and the growing far-right and neo-fascist movement in Europe, US and elsewhere is scary. Capitalism is pushing us slowly but surely into fascism, largely helped by far-right billionaires like Elon Musk, &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Vincent_Bollor%C3%A9&#34;&gt;Vincent Boloré&lt;/a&gt; or &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.disconnect.blog/p/the-conservative-tech-alliance-is-coming-to-canada&#34;&gt;Tobias Lütke&lt;/a&gt;, and it is hard to see any efficient strategy to counter it.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
